<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Assignment_1</string>


    <string name="emblem_title">National Emblem of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="Emblemz">The National Emblem of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh. The national flower Shapla (water lily) is surrounded by two sheaves of rice. Above the water lilly are four stars and a three jute leaves. The national emblem of Bangladesh was adopted shortly after independence in 1971. Located on the emblem is a water lily, that is bordered on two sides by rice sheaves. Above the water lilly are four stars and a three connected jute leaves. The water lily is the country’s national flower, and is representative of the many rivers that run through Bangladesh. Rice represents its presence as the staple food of Bangladesh, and for the agriculture of that nation. The four stars represent the four founding principles in the current constitution of Bangladesh of 1972: nationalism, secularism, socialism, and democracy.
</string>


    <string name="flag">With a red circle — which represents the rising sun and the bloody sacrifices of countless Bangladeshi people for their freedom — on a bottle green background which symbolizes our wonderful natural resources, the national flag of Bangladesh stands as high as our pride and love for our motherland. The sanctity and the dignity of the National Flag is protected and officially preserved by an act of Bangladesh Flag rules, 1972. As per the rules, the national flag is rectangular in size with the length to width ratio of 10:6. Prescribed sizes of the flag for buildings are 305cm X 183cm, 152cm X 91cm and 76cm X 46cm and for vehicles are 38cm X 23cm and 25cm X 15cm. It was designed by famous artist Kamrul Hasan.</string>
    <string name="flag_title">National Flag of Bangladesh</string>


    <string name="seal_title">National Government Seal of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="seal">The Government Seal of Bangladesh used by the Ministries of Bangladesh and the Government of Bangladesh on official documents. One version is used on the cover page of Bangladeshi passports. The Seal features the same design elements as the first Flag of Bangladesh in a circular setting. The outer white ring is shown with the caption of the official name of the Government of the People’s Republic of Bangladesh in with 4 red 5-pointed stars. In centre the country map on a red disc.</string>


    <string name="flower_title">National Flower of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="flower">The Shapla (Nymphaea nouchali) is the national flower of Bangladesh. Nymphaea nouchali is considered a medicinal plant in Indian Ayurvedic medicine under the name Ambal; it was mainly used to treat indigestion. Recent experiments have confirmed that it has medicinal qualities as an antihepatotoxic and antidiabetic. Like all waterlilies or lotuses, its tubers and rhizomes can be used as food items; they are eaten usually boiled or roasted. In the case of N. nouchali, its tender leaves and flower peduncles are also valued as food.</string>

    <string name="bird_title">National Bird of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="bird">The Magpie Robin (Copsychus saularis) is the national Bird of Bangladesh, where it is common and known as the Doyel or Doel. They are common birds in urban gardens as well as forests. They are particularly well known for their songs. It is a widely used symbol in Bangladesh, appearing on currency notes, and a landmark in the city of Dhaka is named as the Doyel Chatwar (meaning: Doyel Square).</string>

    <string name="animal_title">National Animal of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="animal">The Royal Bengal Tiger (Panthera tigris tigris) is the national animal of Bangladesh. The tiger replaces the lion as King of the Beasts in cultures of eastern Asia representing royalty, fearlessness and wrath. Members of the East Bengal Regiment of the Bangladesh Army are nicked "Bengal Tigers" the regiment’s logo is a tiger face and The Bangladesh Cricket Board’s logo features a Royal Bengal Tiger. Bangladesh teems with icons and symbols, not the least of which is the ubiquitous Royal Bengal Tiger. This majestic beast finds its home in Bangladesh, in the still pristine mangrove forests of the Sundarbans</string>

    <string name="fruit_title">National Fruit of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="fruit">The Jackfruit (Artocarpus heterophyllus) is the national fruit of Bangladesh. It is native to parts of South and Southeast Asia and widely cultivated in tropical regions of Bangladesh. The jackfruit tree is well suited to tropical lowlands, and its fruit is the largest tree-borne fruit, reaching as much as 80 pounds (36 kg) in weight, 36 inches (90 cm) in length, and 20 inches (50 cm) in diameter.</string>

    <string name="fish_title">National Fish of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="fish">The Ilish or Hilsha, also spelled Elish (Tenualosa ilisha), is national fish of Bangladesh. The Ilish is a popular fish to eat among the people of South Asia.</string>

    <string name="poet_title">National Poet of Bangladesh</string>
    <string name="poet">Kazi Nazrul Islam is the ‘National Poet of Bangladesh’. He was an immensely talented person, a gifted literary genius in the field of writing poems and composing songs. He started working quite early in his life to financially support his family which also affected his education. He did numerous jobs in his childhood and later joined the armed forces after matriculation. While serving in the army, he started his literary career, most of which revolved around poetry. Initially he received appreciation and praise for his poetic collections but later the British Empire sensed a bit of hostility and rebellion in his poems and imprisoned him for over a year. During his years in prison, his rebellious and fierce attitude grew deeper and he wrote many such works. After coming out of prison, he encouraged people to fight for independence and also wrote about the weaker classes of the society. Later his focus shifted towards religion due to some personal life incidents. He faced constant struggle in his personal life due to poverty, his wife’s illness, his mental health and the death of his loved ones. Despite all difficulties he emerged out as a revolutionary who managed to leave his imprint in the spheres of music, poetry and writing.</string>


</resources>